Previously on the show. The eye of the storm became smaller and smaller,
Episode sebelumnya. Mata badai makin mengecil,
plunging Balloon City into crisis.
menjerumuskan Kota Balon ke dalam krisis.
Fortunately, Wolffy and the goats
Untungnya, Wolffy dan kambing
joined forces and pulled the entire city away from the storm.
menggabungkan kekuatan dan menarik keluar kota dari badai.
After saying goodbye to the balloons, the goats continued on their journey.
Setelah pamit pada para  balon, kambing melanjutkan perjalanan.
What will they encounter next?
Apa yang akan mereka hadapi?
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: Baby Chief"
Petualangan Langit Pulau Terbang: Pak Kepala Bayi.
How did things turn out this way?
Kenapa keadaannya jadi begini?
Where am I?
Di mana aku?
I wonder how Weslie and the rest are doing.
Bagaimana keadaan Weslie dan yang lain?
I'm so hungry.
Aku lapar sekali.
This is delicious!
Ini lezat!
Wow, that's a huge star.
Itu bintang yang besar.
Whose baby is this?
Bayi siapa ini?
Baby, you're awake.
Bayi, kau sudah sadar.
What's going on?
Ada apa?
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
Come baby, it's time to go home.
Baiklah bayi, waktunya pulang.
When can I become myself again?
Kapan aku bisa menjadi diriku lagi?
Poor goats.
Kambing yang malang.
Good thing I've placed a bug on their Magic Train.
Untung kupasang penyadap di Kereta Ajaib mereka.
Now I'll always know where they are.
Kini aku akan tahu di mana mereka berada.
I think there's something wrong with Wolffy's bug.
Kurasa ada yang salah dengan penyadap Wolffy.
This is my chance for an ambush.
Ini peluangku  untuk penyergapan.
Don't worry. I'll be gentle on you. You won't feel a thing.
Jangan khawatir. Aku akan bersikap lembut. Kau takkan merasakan apa pun.
Watch out, everybody!
Awas, semua!
Wolffy loves to ambush us at times like this.
Wolffy suka menyergap kita di saat seperti ini.
That's right. What can you do about it?
Benar. Kau bisa apa?
Don't worry.
Jangan cemas.
I've put a counter-attack device at the back of Magic Train.
Aku pasang alat serangan balik di belakang Kereta Ajaib.
If he attacks us with a missile,
Jika dia serang kita dengan rudal,
he'll get it instead.
justru akan berbalik menyerangnya.
Fine. If that's so, I'll hit you from the side.
Baiklah. Jika begitu, aku akan memukulmu dari samping.
I've also put chilli powder all over Magic Train.
Aku juga menaruh bubuk cabai di sekitar Kereta Ajaib.
If he hits us, he'll cry from all that chilli.
Jika dia memukul kita, dia akan menangis akibat cabainya.
That was close. I almost hit Magic Train.
Nyaris. Aku hampir pukul Kereta Ajaib
I'll let you off this time and wait for you at your destination.
Aku akan melepaskanmu kali ini dan menunggu di tujuanmu.
Stupid bug! Useless!
Penyadap bodoh! Tak berguna!
Silly Wolffy.
Wolffy Konyol .
They'll never guess that I'm already here waiting for them.
Mereka takkan mengira aku sudah di sini menunggu mereka.
It's still bright out. Why are the streets so empty?
Masih siang. Kenapa jalanannya kosong?
Hey, little guy.
Hei, Pria Kecil.
Wolffy? What is he doing here?
Wolffy? Sedang apa dia di sini?
A goat?
Kambing?
How come he resembles Slowy so much?
Kenapa dia sangat mirip dengan Slowy?
He mustn't know it's me. I'll pretend I don't know him.
Dia pasti sadar ini aku. Aku akan pura-pura tak kenal.
He's so cute!
Dia menggemaskan!
Let me test him.
Biar aku uji dia.
Weslie! You're here!
Weslie! Kau di sini!
Oh no, I fell for it.
Aku tertipu.
I don't know why you are so small,
Entah kenapa kau sangat kecil,
but I'm sure you're Slowy.
tapi aku yakin kau adalah Slowy.
You're running away?
Mau kabur?
You've always been slow.
Kau memang rajin, tapi kau lambat karena masih bayi,
You can struggle all you want in the pot.
Kau bisa berjuang semaumu di kuali.
Cry as you wish. Nobody will come to your rescue.
Menangislah. Tak ada yang akan menyelamatkanmu.
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
How could you make our cute baby cry? Come out, everyone.
Teganya kau buat bayi menangis. Keluarlah, Semua.
Don't be afraid. We'll protect you.
Jangan takut. Kami akan melindungimu.
You haven't answered me yet. Who are you?
Kau tak menjawabku. Siapa kau?
I'm his father!
Aku adalah ayahnya!
I don't believe you.
Aku tak percaya.
Do you have any proof?
Kau punya bukti?
Of course.
Tentu saja.
This is a picture of the two of us.
Ini adalah foto kami berdua.
Wolffy, your photoshop skills are so bad.
Wolffy, kemampuan Photoshop-mu buruk.
Wow, they look alike. Look.
Wah, mereka mirip. Lihat.
He looks just like his father.
Dia amat mirip ayahnya.
Quiet.
Diam.
One photograph doesn't prove anything. Do you have any other proof?
Satu foto tak membuktikan apa pun. Ada bukti lain?
Of course I do.
Tentu saja.
He loves drinking tea, reading the papers, and doing experiments.
Dia suka minum teh, membaca koran, dan bereksperimen.
When he's thinking really hard, grass grows on his head. Look!
Saat dia berpikir keras, rumput tumbuh di kepalanya. Lihat!
I need to think of a solution. I can't allow Wolffy to take me away.
Aku harus cari solusi. Aku tak bisa membiarkan Wolffy merebutku.
He's absolutely right.
Dia benar sekali.
Yes.
Ya.
And also--
- Dan juga... - Baiklah.
You know him so well. You must really be his father.
Kau sangat mengenal dia. Kau pasti ayahnya.
I'm glad you're finally reunited.
Aku senang kau akhirnya bersatu kembali.
The only thing I can do now is... run!
Satu-satunya hal yang bisa kupikirkan adalah lari!
Wrong way. Your dad's right here.
Salah jalan. Ayahmu ada di sini
Come to papa, son. Let papa hold you.
Datanglah kepada Ayah, Nak Biarkan ayah memelukmu.
Don't forget to feed him and put him to bed.
Jangan lupa untuk memberinya makan dan menidurkannya.
Cover him well at night.
Selimuti dia di malam hari.
And remember to--
Dan ingat untuk...
See you all!
Sampai jumpa!
Thanks for taking care of my son the last few days.
Terima kasih sudah urus putraku beberapa hari terakhir.
Baby!
Bayi!
Save me!
Selamatkan aku!
My heart is telling me that I really miss the baby!
Hatiku bilang bahwa aku sangat merindukan bayi itu!
Who would've known?
Siapa sangka?
The wise and intelligent Slowy has turned into a baby.
Slowy yang bijak dan cerdas berubah menjadi bayi.
I'll absorb your energy first before eating you.
Aku akan serap energimu dulu sebelum memakanmu.
Do you think you can run away from me?
Kau pikir bisa kabur dariku?
No! They're very expensive!
Tidak! Itu mahal sekali.
That's Wolnie's favorite perfume!
Itu parfum kesukaan Wolnie!
No!
Tidak!
Slowy!
Slowy!
I'll teach you a lesson!
- Kau akan kuberi pelajaran! - Jangan sakiti bayinya!
It's you again? Stay out of this.
Kau lagi? Jangan ikut campur.
You're not his father. He's so cute.
Kau bukan ayahnya. Dia lucu sekali.
How could you make him cry? That's unforgivable!
Kenapa kau bisa buat dia menangis? Tak bisa diterima!
Slowy! I'll get you!
Slowy! Aku akan menangkapmu!
I'm going to get you!
Aku akan menangkapmu!
How could you still be mean to him? I must teach you a lesson.
Kenapa kau kejam kepadanya? Aku harus memberimu pelajaran.
You? I can beat ten of you easily.
Kau? Aku bisa kalahkan kalian dengan mudah.
Is that so?
Benarkah?
How come you're all here?
Kalian masih di sini?
Just like you, we miss the baby so much.
Seperti kau, kami sangat merindukan bayinya.
We just wanted to see him.
Aku ingin melihatnya.
Hey, listen. Be smart.
Dengar. Cerdaslah.
Leave the goat here and go.
Tinggalkan kambingnya dan pergi.
It's not fair! I was outnumbered.
Tidak adil! Aku kalah jumlah.
I'll be back!
Aku akan kembali!
Don't worry. We won't let bad guys take you away again.
Tenang. Kami takkan biarkan penjahat membawamu pergi.
We finally arrived here safely, thanks to my superior flying skills.
Akhirnya tiba, ini berkat kemampuan terbangku.
Is that so?
Benarkah?
You took us the wrong way.
Kau yang salah rute!
We could've arrived here three hours ago.
Kita bisa tiba di sini tiga jam lalu.
This place looks so peculiar.
Tempat ini tampak menyenangkan.
Wow! What a huge star!
Wah! Bintang yang besar!
I wonder if Jonie and the chief are here.
Aku ingin tahu apa Jonie dan Pak Kepala ada di sini.
This place is huge. How will we find them?
Tempat ini besar sekali. Bagaimana mencarinya?
The residents here are all stars!
Semua warga di sini adalah bintang!
That baby looks so much like the chief!
Bayi itu sangat mirip Pak Kepala!
Wow, they do look similar!
Mereka memang mirip!
Is that actually the chief?
Apa itu sungguh Pak Kepala?
Kids!
Anak-anak!
What do you want from the baby?
Mau apa dengan bayi ini?
We're the chief's family.
Kami keluarga Pak Kepala.
Who is the chief?
Siapa Pak Kepala?
He's Slowy, the chief of Goats Village.
Dia Slowy, Kepala Desa Kambing.
You're lying!
Kau bohong!
It's the truth. Please believe us.
Itu yang sebenarnya. Percayalah.
If you don't believe us, we can tell you what he's like.
Jika tak percaya, kami bisa cerita sikap dia.
He likes reading papers, drinking tea, and doing experiments.
Dia suka membaca koran, minum teh, dan bereksperimen.
When he thinks, a blade of grass grows on his head.
dia berpikir, rumput tumbuh di kepalanya.
That's exactly what he said! You're lying!
Itu persis yang dia katakan! Kau bohong!
Wait! We have a picture of all of us.
Tunggu! Ada foto kami semua.
This was photoshopped!
Ini hasil tipuan!
Our baby doesn't look that old!
Bayi kami tidak tua!
They're telling the truth.
Mereka bicara jujur!
Baby, calm down. We won't let anyone take you away again.
Bayi, tenanglah. Takkan kubiarkan kau direbut dariku.
You liars! Go away!
Kalian pembohong. Pergi!
We're not liars. We won't leave without our chief.
Kami tak berbohong. Kita takkan pergi tanpa Pak Kepala.
You won't leave?
Kau takkan pergi?
No!
Tidak!
Will you leave?
Bisakah kau pergi?
If you don't leave, we will!
Kalau kau tak pergi, kami yang pergi.
Kids!
Anak-anak!
Chief!
Pak Kepala!